<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[/* steve jansen */]]></title>
  <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-28T22:07:40-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://steve-jansen.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Jansen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to modify the TCP/IP port binding for the Microsoft Web Deployment Agent Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.com/blog/2013/02/28/how-to-modify-the-tcp-slash-ip-port-binding-for-the-microsoft-web-deployment-agent-service/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-28T16:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://steve-jansen.github.com/blog/2013/02/28/how-to-modify-the-tcp-slash-ip-port-binding-for-the-microsoft-web-deployment-agent-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love shell scripting, which is probably why I seem to somehow get organically involved in &#8220;DevOps&#8221; on most of my project work.  I&#8217;m drafting up a series of posts on tips and tricks for shell scripts (with love for both Windows and *nix) - it seems to be a fading art among recent comp sci grads.  Until I finish those posts, I wanted to share a quick script I wrote to reassign the TCP/IP port binding for Microsoft&#8217;s Web Deployment Agent service.</p>

<p>This is my attempt to refine a very good answer posted a couple years ago <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/5867392/can-the-web-deploy-agent-run-on-a-port-other-than-80-on-iis6">asking if web deploy can run on a port other than 80</a>.  Why, yes it can&#8230;</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/5060329.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code></code></pre></noscript></div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A ghost no more]]></title>
    <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.com/blog/2013/02/25/a-ghost-no-more/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-25T12:49:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://steve-jansen.github.com/blog/2013/02/25/a-ghost-no-more</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blogging has long been on my todo list &#8211; quite frankly too long.  A colleague shared <a href="http://www.troyhunt.com/2013/02/the-ghost-who-codes-how-anonymity-is.html">a great piece by Troy Hunt named &#8220;The ghost who codes: how anonymity is killing your career&#8221;</a>.  Troy inspired me that I need to make the time to just get it done.  So this is where I start giving back whatever small knowledge bits I may have.</p>

<p>I am fortunate enough to be with a company now that encourages professional writing, which hasn&#8217;t always been the case.  Troy&#8217;s article really resonated with me that developers have an insatiatable appetite for consuming knowledge.  We take information all the time, and there&#8217;s a duty on all our parts to give back and not just take.  Thanks to both Troy any my colleague Alex for pushing me to do more!</p>

<p>Many years ago I learned an metaphor from a very accomplished veteran of the US military that is quite applicable to coding: &#8220;you have to either be tough or smart to succeed&#8221;.  Say you want to navigate from point A to point B, and there just happens to be a tall mountain between the two points.  The tough guy takes a straight line route, ardously ascending and descending the mountain.  The smart guy circumnavigates the mountain, saving time and energy.</p>

<p>I know developers like to be the smartest person in the room, but, I am self-aware enough to admit I often fall into the &#8220;tough&#8221; camp - hacking into the late hours until the job is done.  I suppose this blog will be a true measure of how many (or how few) smart/clever ideas I have up my sleeve!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
