<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: jenkins | /* steve jansen */]]></title>
  <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.io/blog/categories/jenkins/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-16T18:46:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://steve-jansen.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Jansen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Binding Jenkins to port 80 on SUSE Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.io/blog/2014/03/05/binding-jenkins-to-port-80-on-suse/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-05T18:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://steve-jansen.github.io/blog/2014/03/05/binding-jenkins-to-port-80-on-suse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been helping an awesome colleague on DevOps for our Jenkins farm, which we use
for continuous integration and continuous deployment to our preproduction environments.</p>

<p>We are really trying to do it right:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use Puppet to provision the Jenkins master, Linux VM build slaves, Windows VM slaves,
and even OS X bare metal slaves (for iOS builds)</li>
<li>Automated backups of Jenkins config files to a private GitHub repo for disster recovery</li>
<li>Patches the GitHub OAuth plugin to make sure you have the same collaborator permissions
(read/write/admin) in a Jenkins job as you do the GitHub repo.</li>
<li>Have a Jenkins staging environment to test upgrades to Jenkins and plugins to avoid surprises.</li>
<li>Run Jenkins on the Long Term Support (LTS) release channel to avoid surprises.</li>
</ul>


<p>I wish my shop used CentOS or Debian; sadly we are stuck on SUSE Enterprise.  SUSE is really
good at turning 5 minute tasks on CentOS or Debian into uber frustrating hour-long ordeals.</p>

<p>One of the glitches we faced was running the Jenkins web UI on port 80.  SUSE lacks the
authbind package for binding to port below port 1024 as a non-root user.  We wanted to run the
Jenkins deamon as a regular privilege user, so running as root was not an option.</p>

<p>We are currently smoke testing this LSB <code>/etc/init.d/jenkins.portforwarding</code> script, which is
just a wrapper around <code>iptables</code>.  So far, it seems to get the job done.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/9361161.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>#!/bin/sh
#
#     SUSE system statup script for port forwarding port 80 to the port
#     for the Jenkins continuous build server.
#
#     Jenkins normally does not run as root, thus /etc/init.d/jenkins cannot
#     bind to ports &lt; 1024 since SUSE does not support authbind (or similar).
#
#     The MIT License (MIT)
#
#     Copyright (C) 2014 Steve Jansen
#
#     Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
#     of this software and associated documentation files (the &quot;Software&quot;), to deal
#     in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
#     to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
#     copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
#     furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:
#
#     The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
#     all copies or substantial portions of the Software.
#
#     THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
#     IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
#     FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
#     AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
#     LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
#     OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
#     THE SOFTWARE.
#
### BEGIN INIT INFO
# Provides:          jenkins.portforwarding
# Required-Start:    jenkins
# Should-Start:
# Required-Stop:     jenkins
# Should-Stop:
# Default-Start:     3 5
# Default-Stop:      0 1 2 6
# Short-Description: Port forwarding for Jenkins continuous build server
# Description:       Forward port 80 traffic to the Jenkins continuous build server
### END INIT INFO

# Check for existence of needed config file and read it
JENKINS_CONFIG=/etc/sysconfig/jenkins
JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT=80

test -r &quot;$JENKINS_CONFIG&quot; || { echo &quot;$JENKINS_CONFIG not existing&quot;;
  if [ &quot;$1&quot; = &quot;stop&quot; ]; then exit 0;
  else exit 6; fi; }

# Read config
. &quot;$JENKINS_CONFIG&quot;

. /etc/rc.status
rc_reset # Reset status of this service

if [ &quot;$JENKINS_PORT&quot; -eq &quot;$JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT&quot; ]
then
  echo &quot;Jenkins already running on port $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT, skipping port forwarding&quot;
  rc_exit
fi

readonly iptables_table=&quot;-t nat&quot;
readonly base_rule=&quot;-p tcp --dport $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT -j REDIRECT --to-ports $JENKINS_PORT&quot;
readonly external_rule=&quot;PREROUTING -p tcp -m tcp --dport $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT -j REDIRECT --to-ports $JENKINS_PORT&quot;
readonly loopback_rule=&quot;OUTPUT -p tcp -m tcp --dport $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT -j REDIRECT --to-ports $JENKINS_PORT&quot;

check_status ()
{
  iptables-save $iptables_table | grep -- &quot;$external_rule&quot; &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1 &amp;&amp; iptables-save $iptables_table | grep -- &quot;$loopback_rule&quot; &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1
  return $?
}

case &quot;$1&quot; in
  start)
      check_status
      if [ $? -eq 0 ]
      then
        echo &quot;Jenkins port forwarding already forwarding port $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT to port $JENKINS_PORT&quot;
        rc_exit
      fi

      echo &quot;Starting Jenkins port forwarding&quot;
      echo &quot;Enabling iptables port forwarding from port $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT to port $JENKINS_PORT&quot;
      iptables $iptables_table -A $external_interface $external_rule &amp;&amp; iptables $iptables_table -A $loopback_rule
      result=$?

      if [ $result -eq 0 ]
      then
        rc_status -v
      else
        rc_failed $result
        rc_status -v
      fi
    ;;
  stop)
      check_status
      if [ $? -ne 0 ]
      then
        echo &quot;Jenkins port forwarding already stopped&quot;
        rc_exit
      fi

      echo &quot;Disabling iptables port forwarding from port $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT to port $JENKINS_PORT&quot;
      iptables $iptables_table -D $external_interface $external_rule &amp;&amp; iptables $iptables_table -D $loopback_rule
      result=$?

      if [ $result -eq 0 ]
      then
        rc_status -v
      else
        rc_failed $result
        rc_status -v
      fi
    ;;
  restart)
      $0 stop
      $0 start
      rc_status
    ;;
    status)
      echo &quot;Checking status of iptables port forwarding from port $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT to port $JENKINS_PORT&quot;
      check_status
      result=$?

      if [ $result -eq 0 ]
      then
        echo &quot;Port forwarding from port $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT to port $JENKINS_PORT is enabled&quot;
        rc_status -v
      else
        echo &quot;Port forwarding from port $JENKINS_FORWARD_PORT to port $JENKINS_PORT is disabled&quot;
        rc_failed $result
        rc_status -v
      fi
    ;;
  *)
      echo &quot;Usage: $0 {start|stop|status}&quot;
      exit 1
    ;;
esac
rc_exit
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>If all goes well, I will merge this logic into a pull request for the <a href="https://github.com/jenkinsci/jenkins/blob/master/opensuse/SOURCES/jenkins.init.in">Jenkins init.d script for OpenSuse</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
