<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: git | /* steve jansen */]]></title>
  <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.io/blog/categories/git/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-05T21:06:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://steve-jansen.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steve Jansen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A better FTP client for Windows you already have: Git bash's curl command]]></title>
    <link href="http://steve-jansen.github.io/blog/2014/02/15/a-better-ftp-client-for-windows-you-already-have-gits-curl-command/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-15T17:24:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://steve-jansen.github.io/blog/2014/02/15/a-better-ftp-client-for-windows-you-already-have-gits-curl-command</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My shop has a couple of internal FTP servers to mirror commonly used installers for .Net devs.
Installers for apps like Visual Studio can be huge, so GitHub isn&rsquo;t the best place for this, and
it would also smoke most of our Dropbox quotas.  So an FTP server seems like the 3rd best option.</p>

<p>We are a geographically distributed team, with a VPN to access internal servers.  Even with a reliable
VPN session over ISP fiber connection, I&rsquo;ve experience lots of realiability problems downloading large files
with the native Windows Explorer / Internet Explorer FTP.</p>

<p>The Windows ftp command line client can be a pain to work with.  Fortunately, the Git bash emulator for Windows
(msysgit) includes a MinGW port of the awesome <code>curl</code> utility.  The <code>curl</code> utility has all kinds of awesome features
for downloading large files.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a few options I found really useful:</p>

<p><code>bash
curl -C - -v -O "ftp://ftp.example.com/path/to/file.zip"
</code></p>

<ul>
<li><code>-C -</code> option tells bash to automatically continue an interrupted download, if the server supports this feature.</li>
<li><code>-v</code> prints verbose stats, including an dynamic progress info</li>
<li><code>-O</code> automatically saves the file using the remote file name to the current working directory</li>
</ul>


<p>I crafted this gist to enable downloading a large number of binaries related to .Net development from our FTP server.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/9378219.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;You are being &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gist/9378219&quot;&gt;redirected&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Be warned, this hack spawns a new command prompt window for each download, so it can get a bit crazy.  This seemed like
the best worst way to download in parallel while also making sense of each download&rsquo;s status.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
